Matheus **Torquato**

Where to find me

Swansea, Wales United Kingdom Matheusft@gmail.com

Expertise

Artificial Intelligence,
Machine Learning,
Data Science, Data
Mining, Embedded
Computing, Digital
Systems,
Reconfigurable
Computing and
Human-Computer
Interaction.

Skills

Python, MATLAB,
TensorFlow, Scikit
Learn, Pandas,
NumPy, SciPy, Version
control systems,
Translating complex
scientific concepts to
non-experts,
Proactivity,
Organisation,
Communication,
Responsibility and
Discipline

Languages

English Portuguese

Summary

BEng and MSc in Computer Engineering. Two years of experience in applying Machine Learning to manufacturing processes. Expertise in scientific and applied research in the topics of Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, Embedded Computing, Digital Systems and Human-Computer Interaction. Well-developed skills employing scientific methods through experimental design, exploratory data analysis and hypothesis testing. Enthusiastic about utilising novel analytical approaches to address real-world challenges and improve commercial outcomes with data. Looking to learn on a daily basis, knowledge is never too much.

Experience

2018 - Now **ASTUTE 2020**

Swansea, UK

Project Assistant (Machine Learning) - June to Now

- Leading the development of projects involving machine learning, data science, computer vision and optimisation.
- Designing regression, classification and predictive models for processes in the Welsh manufacturing sector.
- Delivering actionable insights from industrial datasets focusing on supporting managerial informed decisions.
- Writing collaborative technical project proposals, specifying data and engineering requirements.

2015 - 2015 Tata Steel

Port Talbot, UK

Process Control Engineering Trainee - September to October

- Developed a mobile app (VB programming language) for logging field measurements, previously performed manually.
- Collaborated in the selection of power metering devices for updating the company's high voltage substation network.

2014 - 2014 Petrobras

Natal, Brazil

Engineering Intern - March to May

 Assisted in the final stage of a Programmable Logic Controller ladder code development

2014 - 2014 National Institute for Space Research (INPE)

Natal, Brazil

Engineering Intern - January to March

 Coded a frequency-based signal detecting software (MATLAB) used by low altitude satellites.

Education

2016 - 2017 MSc Computer Engineering

UFRN - Natal, Brazil

Final Mark: 10/10 | Included a period in the SMART Lab (Ottawa, Canada) as a visiting researcher.

2014 - 2015 One Year Abroad Computer Science Swansea University - Swansea, Wales, UK Final Mark: 7.1/10 | Scholarship awarded from the Science Without Borders Programme.

2010 - 2015 **BEng** Computer Engineering

UFRN - Natal, Brazil

Final Mark: 9.6/10 | Result among the top 0.15% highest in the history of this undergraduate course.

Awards

2017	Emerging Leaders in the Americas Program (ELAP) Scholarship targeting the development of high-impact human capital and the next generation of leaders in the Americas.
2016	3rd Place - Intel Embedded Systems Competition 2016 João Pessoa, Brazil Development of a tactile glove device built using an Intel Galileo Board and additional peripheral electronics.
2016	Academic Merit Medal UFRN, Natal, RN, Brazil Honour to whom achieves the highest overall graduation mark.
2015	BBC University newsHACK Challenge Cardiff - Wales Won the category "Deliver the news" after proposing a personalised News experience that was shaped according to user's preferences.
2014	1st Place - Maker Competition 2014 Swansea University, Swansea - Wales Best project in an annual competition held by Swansea University Computer Science department. The project used hardware boards (Arduino and Raspberry Pi) to build a wireless automated house powered by software written in Java, C and Python languages.

Important Publications

2020	Journal Paper (Under Development) Convolutional Neural Network Applied to SARS-CoV-2 Sequence Classification.
2020	Journal Paper (Under Review) Evaluating the burden of COVID-19 in Bahia, Brazil: A modeling analysis of 14.8 million individuals
2020	Journal Paper (Under Review) Multi-objective Optimisation of Electric Arc Furnace Using the NSGA-II Evolutionary Algorithm.
2020	Journal Paper Proposal of the CAD System for Melanoma Detection Using Reconfigurable Computing
2019	Journal Paper Proposal of the Tactile Glove Device. Sensors
2019	Journal Paper Microprocessors and Microsystems A parallel implementation of sequential minimal optimization on FPGA.
2019	Journal Paper Circuits, Systems, and Signal Processing High-Performance Parallel Implementation of Genetic Algorithm on FPGA.
2019	Journal Paper Parallel Implementation of Reinforcement Learning Q-Learning Technique for FPGA.
2016	Journal Paper - (Honorable Mention) Emergeables: Deformable Displays for Continuous Eyes-Free Mobile Interaction.

Additional Activities

2020	Online Course Quantitative Finance & Algorithmic Trading in Pytho	Udemy
2018	Online Course Introduction to User Experience	University of Michigan - edX